<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Chris Rouffer's Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Personal musings, interests, and other things that keep me from sleeping too much]]></description><link>https://chrisrouffer.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 18:01:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[New Beginnings]]></title><description><![CDATA[It’s always fun to start something new. I love starting to read a new book, play a new video game, begin a project, or try out a hobby.
At…]]></description><link>https://chrisrouffer.com//new-beginnings/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrisrouffer.com//new-beginnings/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 12:21:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It’s always fun to start something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love starting to read a new book, play a new video game, begin a project, or try out a hobby.
At the beginning I am always full of energy and passion.  I’ll devote hours or even days
to whatever it is.  As time passes, however, my interest sometimes tapers off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I do manage to finish a lot of what I start, I have to admit that there are a lot of things I haven’t seen through to completion.
My bookshelf has quite a few unfinished books.  My game library is full of games that didn’t hold my attention.
Hobbies are interesting, but some of them only for a while.  Getting a project “Mostly done” or “good enough”
is fine with me in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“Why” is the difference-maker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the “Why” is important to me, then it will be worth the effort.  Some of my recent “Whys”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spent hours on a quirky game.  Why?  The game had a good system of accomplishments and things to try next.  It was relaxing and peaked my curiosity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ate a lot of chocolate over the holidays.  Why?  It tasted great, and I loved the sugar-rush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stopped eating a lot of junk.  Why?  It ran afoul of my other fitness and health goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read a book by an author that I’d never heard of.  Why?  Someone suggested it as a really good book&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m reading every other book by that author.  Why?  I really learned a lot from the first one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other ones that come to mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spending time and money to build a guitar because I wanted the challenge, and because it produced something useful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drag my lazy self to the dojo multiple times per week because I’m always training for the next level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invest hours of rehearsal into guitar, bass, or drums, because I get a huge thrill out of playing live music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I have a “Why” then I can usually stay with it.  I’m hoping that the “Whys” I have for this blog
will keep me on track, and help me to stay with it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Why am I writing this blog?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn, or improve, my own skills:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share things that I am passionate about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Engineering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martial Arts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create and cultivate a “Personal Brand”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that you, the reader, are able to find some use or enjoyment in the posts I make, and that I stay true to the “Whys” that started this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>