<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Chris Rouffer's Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Personal musings, interests, and other things that keep me from sleeping too much]]></description><link>https://chrisrouffer.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 23:39:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Better Ideas in 20 Minutes a Day]]></title><description><![CDATA[“Thinking is the hardest work there is, which is probably the reason why so few engage in it.” — Henry Ford Imagine what would happen to…]]></description><link>https://chrisrouffer.com//better-ideas-in-20-minutes-a-day/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrisrouffer.com//better-ideas-in-20-minutes-a-day/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 18:15:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Thinking is the hardest work there is, which is probably the reason why so few engage in it.” — Henry Ford&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine what would happen to your thinking if you were to get the best thoughts from 12 very great thinkers every year.  Even if these 12 “Great minds” all disagreed with each other, you’d still open your minds and expand your thinking in remarkable ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have a revolutionary idea: We should all spend 20 minutes a day reading a real book, one that has actually been published.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us spend a lot of time every day on social media, watching TV, or reading online news. What if we took 20 minutes of that time to read a book instead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just now I just took the time to carefully read one page out of a book. That page took me almost exactly 2 minutes to read.  With my lightning quick math skills, I calculate that in 20 minutes I could read 10 pages.  If I were to do that every day I’d be learning from 300 pages of edited, vetted and approved writing per month.  This is text that is proven to marketable and intelligent, or at least convincing enough to spend time and money publishing it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine the effects of consuming 1 book per month.  It almost doesn’t matter what book. Each author has their own take on the world. Each genre has its own spin.  All of these intelligible thoughts add up to help us form our own ideas and sharpen our own perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Books are typically well thought-out.  They are read (and re-read), edited, and refined, all before ever being published. Books are full of ideas that have been through multiple levels of scrutiny. They have been invested in, or even slaved over. If a book makes it all the way to the printer it should be respected.  If it makes enough of an impact to get your attention, it likely can teach you something worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to buy books. You can borrow them from friends. You can go to a library. Read whatever you like! Fiction, non-fiction, history, drama, horror… If it was worth publishing, it’s probably worth reading. In one way or another, that book will expand your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I challenge you to take 20 minutes every day to read an actual, published book, paper, ebook, or audiobook. It will enrich your life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Early Spring Cleaning]]></title><description><![CDATA[Early Spring Cleaning I’ve made a mess:  I have articles and blog posts across a bunch of platforms.  After trying a few different solutions…]]></description><link>https://chrisrouffer.com//apologies-for-the-reposts/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrisrouffer.com//apologies-for-the-reposts/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 17:41:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Early Spring Cleaning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve made a mess:  I have articles and blog posts across a bunch of platforms.  After trying a few different solutions, I am finally ready to do some cleaning.  Over the next while I’m moving everything onto &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrisrouffer.com&quot;&gt;my domain&lt;/a&gt;, then sharing out to other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I apologize in advance if get notices for reposts of some of my older writings or articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While moving things I’ll take the opportunity to edit, refine, and improve my content. Consider it a 2nd edition, with improved clarity and accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your patience and understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[New Beginnings]]></title><description><![CDATA[It’s always fun to start something new. I love starting to read a new book, play a new video game, begin a project, or try out a hobby.
At…]]></description><link>https://chrisrouffer.com//new-beginnings/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrisrouffer.com//new-beginnings/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 12:21:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It’s always fun to start something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love starting to read a new book, play a new video game, begin a project, or try out a hobby.
At the beginning I am always full of energy and passion.  I’ll devote hours or even days
to whatever it is.  As time passes, however, my interest sometimes tapers off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I do manage to finish a lot of what I start, I have to admit that there are a lot of things I haven’t seen through to completion.
My bookshelf has quite a few unfinished books.  My game library is full of games that didn’t hold my attention.
Hobbies are interesting, but some of them only for a while.  Getting a project “Mostly done” or “good enough”
is fine with me in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“Why” is the difference-maker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/1591846447/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=15121&amp;creative=330641&amp;creativeASIN=1591846447&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=chrisrouffe09-20&amp;linkId=f56c7c33b7278cddc9ddbfcdd8aecb48&quot;&gt;Start with Why: How Great Leaders Inspire Everyone to Take Action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//ir-ca.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=chrisrouffe09-20&amp;l=am2&amp;o=15&amp;a=1591846447&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the “Why” is important to me, then it will be worth the effort.  Some of my recent “Whys”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spent hours on a quirky game.  Why?  The game had a good system of accomplishments and things to try next.  It was relaxing and peaked my curiosity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ate a lot of chocolate over the holidays.  Why?  It tasted great, and I loved the sugar-rush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stopped eating a lot of junk.  Why?  It ran afoul of my other fitness and health goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read a book by an author that I’d never heard of.  Why?  Someone suggested it as a really good book&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m reading every other book by that author.  Why?  I really learned a lot from the first one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other ones that come to mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spending time and money to build a guitar because I wanted the challenge, and because it produced something useful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drag my lazy self to the dojo multiple times per week because I’m always training for the next level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invest hours of rehearsal into guitar, bass, or drums, because I get a huge thrill out of playing live music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I have a “Why” then I can usually stay with it.  I’m hoping that the “Whys” I have for this blog
will keep me on track, and help me to stay with it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Why am I writing this blog?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn, or improve, my own skills:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share things that I am passionate about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Engineering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martial Arts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create and cultivate a “Personal Brand”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that you, the reader, are able to find some use or enjoyment in the posts I make, and that I stay true to the “Whys” that started this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>